Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy, Dean's Office; Records ua680
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Hannah B. Applebaum Files, 1963-1971; 8; 0.5 cubic ft.
  - H. Applebaum, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 2)
  - H. Applebaum, 1967 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 3)
  - H. Applebaum, 1968 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 4)
  - H. Applebaum, 1969 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 5)
  - H. Applebaum, 1970 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 6)
  - H. Applebaum, 1971 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 7)
  - H. Applebaum - Faculty Meetings, 1965-1966 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 8)
  - H. Applebaum - Faculty Meetings, 1967 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 9)
  - H. Applebaum - Faculty Meetings, 1968 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 10)
  - H. Applebaum - Faculty Meetings, 1969 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 11)
  - H. Applebaum Files, Miscellaneous, 1963-1970 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 12)
  - H. Applebaum Files - Official Memos, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (8-Hannah B. Applebaum Files), Folder 13)
- Murray Nathan Files, 1946-1960; 9; 0.66 cubic ft.
  Arranged by the Organization & Methods (O&M) Program number
  This series contains program information, bibliographies and later reading materials relating to the Conferences on Organization and Methods (hereafter O&M). Murray Nathan was the Director of the Office of Planning & Procedures in the New York State Department of Health.[63] The first state organizational unit devoted to the examination of methods and procedures was established within the State Insurance Fund in 1935, The Office of Planning and Procedures was established in the New York State Department of Health on April 16, 1946, following the example of other state agencies.[64] Murray Nathan was also a member of the Professional Training Committee of the Capital District Chapter of the American Society of Public Administration (ASPA).[65] The first O & M Program was organized by the New York State Management Improvement Branch, Bureau of the Budget, in cooperation with the Inter-Departmental Committee on Organization & Methods Staff Improvement in October 1946. The first program series was offered October 25-November 8, 1946.[66] The first nine O&M conferences were New York conferences; while the "O&M I O" folder contains information concerning the Interagency Records Conference conducted by the National Archives in 1949-50. Additional information regarding the Capital District Chapter of ASPA is contained in the records of the American Society for Public Administration (ASPA), Empire State Capital Area Chapter (APAP009). The Capital District Chapter of ASPA was founded in 1945 and renamed the Empire State Capital Area Chapter in 1989.[67] The majority of records in this series relate to public administration and management theory and New York State programs. The "O&M I" folder contains a final examination from the GSPA course "Administration Methods and Managerial Control" from January, 1950. A copy of "Education for Public Administration in New York State (Proposed Program)" written by the Capital District Chapter of ASPA (1953) can be found in the "Origins 1950-55, 1960" folder in Series 11, Subseries 9 - The History Files.
  - 0 & M 2, ca. 1946-1959 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 14)
  - 0 & M 3 Production Planning, 1946-1952 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 15)
  - 0 & M 4 Organization, 1946-1952 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 16)
  - 0 & M 5 Surveys & Reports Operation Audit, 1946-1953 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 17)
  - 0 & M 6 The Human Element, 1946-1955; 1960 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 18)
  - 0 & M 7 Management Controls Measurement Cost & Analysis Audit, 1946-1953 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 19)
  - 0 & M 7a Management Controls cont. Work Measurement, ca. 1946-1953 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 20)
  - 0 & M 8 Administrative Issuances & Forms Including Procedures & Manuals, ca. 1946-1953 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 21)
  - 0 & M 8a Forms, ca. 1946-1953 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 22)
  - 0 & M 9 Records & Files Communication Business Machinery Space, ca. 1946-1947 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 23)
  - 0 & M 10 Interagency Records & Administration Conference (Federal), 1949-1950 (Box 1 (9-Murray Nathan Files), Folder 24)
- Student Research Papers, 1963-1975; 10; 2 cubic ft.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Must consult an archivist to view student papers.
  Series arranged chronologically by year of publication. Papers are then arranged alphabetically by department (if known) first, and then by alphabetically by paper title.
  This series consists of research papers, essays and theses written by students in master's programs at GPSA. The majority of the papers are single works, but there are two items that contain multiple student papers on single themes. These are Student Papers on Federal Programs Volumes 1 & 2 - PA 500 Class, Spring 1975 and Personnel Administration in the State of New York Volumes I & 2, Spring 1967.
  - GSPA Research Papers & Studies, "FCC & Public Interest Regarding the Passage of the All-Channel TV Receiver Legislation", ca. 1963 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 1)
  - GSPA Research Papers & Studies, "The Clearing & Snagging Project of Oneonta, NY..." GSPA Masters Essays, ca. 1964 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 2)
  - GSPA Research Papers & Studies, "School Desegregation in Albany" GSPA Research Essay - Public Affairs, 1969 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 3)
  - GSPA Research Papers & Studies, "Civilian Review Boards: An American Dilemma", 1965 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 4)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "The Full Employment Budget", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 5)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "Medicare: Selected Macroeconomic & Microeconomic Implications", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 6)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "The Contribution of Fixed Point Theorems to the Proofs of Existence of Solutions for General Completion Economic Equilibrium", 1969 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 7)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "A Study of District 50, UMWA", 1968 February (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 8)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "Revenue Estimating in the NYS Department of Taxation & Financing", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 9)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Economy, "A Role for Forestry in Economic Government", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 10)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "NYS Public Employment Labor Relations Under the Taylor Law", 1968 June 19 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 11)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "The Role a Political Party Can Play in National Integration: A Case Study of the Alliance", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 12)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Daniel Deleon, American Marxist", 1968 August (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 13)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Foundations of Power in 20 Century Iran", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 14)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "The Nature of the Appeal of The Assembly of Captive European Nations A Foreign Policy Interest Group", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 15)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Personnel Issues in the Administration of Federally Aided Assistance Programs", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 16)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Soviet National Policy & the Sino Soviet Dispute", 1968 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 17)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "The Revival of the Community: A Reaction to Elitist-Pluralist Community Studies & on the Application of the Perspective of the Public Problems Process", 1968 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 18)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Participation as a Factor in the Political Development of a One-Party Dominant State: Mexico", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 19)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "The Determination of Necessity", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 20)
  - GSPA Research Essay - Political Science, "Unshared Self Images & French American Relations", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 21)
  - GSPA Research Paper - Political Science, "Factors Promoting Effective State Government: The Stateof New York", 1967 June 7 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 22)
  - GSPA Research Study - Political Science, "A Study of Task Orientations of Chairman of Majority & Minority Political Parties", 1969 November (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 23)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "Subsidies: An Annotated Bibliography", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 24)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "Religion Politics & Social Change", 1967 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 25)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "Great Politics: The Sublimation of the Political", 1967 June (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 26)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "Economic Impact of Federal Installations on Public Schools: An Evaluation of Public Law 81-874 - A Case Study", 1969 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 27)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "The Impact of the US Foreign Agricultural Trade Policy on the Developing Nations" (2 copies), 1969 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 28)
  - GSPA Research Essay, "The Growth Potential of Counties in NYS", 1971 August 13 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 29)
  - GSPA Research Papers "Personnel Administration in the State of NY" Vol. 1, 1967 Spring (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 30)
  - GSPA Research Papers "Personnel Administration in the State of NY" Vol. 2, 1967 Spring (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 31)
  - GSPA Master's Thesis - Political Science, "The Effect of International Trusteeship Upon the Political Development of Tanganyika", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 32)
  - GSPA Master's Thesis - Political Science, "Service, Salience & the Submarine: An Analysis of Constituency Influence on Representation", October 25, 1968 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 33)
  - GSPA Master's Thesis - Political Science, "Gov. Rockefeller & Assembly Republicans, 1959-65: A Roll Call Analysis of 'Noe' Votes in NYS", ca. 1967 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 34)
  - GSPA Master's Thesis - Political Science, "Inconsistency in Indian Policy Hyderbad & GOA", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 35)
  - GSPA Master's Thesis - Political Science, "Urban Renewal in Mapleview: Analysis of Decisions", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 36)
  - Student Papers on Federal Programs, Vol. I "Social Services & Revenue Sharing" - PA 500 Class, 1975 Spring (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 37)
    Must consult an archivist to view this material.
  - Student Papers on Federal Programs, Vol. 2 "Regulatory, Agricultural & Misc. Programs" - PA 500 Class, 1975 Spring (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous student papers, "Selected Bibliography of Books on Asian Government & Politics since 1947 - 1966", Undated (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous student papers, Working Notes for Speech, "Administrative Adjudication in Social Welfare", 1966 (Box 1 (10-Student Research Papers), Folder 40)
- Oversized, 1946-1984; 11
  - Budget Requests, 1982-1983; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 1)
  - Budget Requests, 1981-1982; 1982-1983 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 3)
  - Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 6)
  - Temporary Service-Allocation Plan, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 7)
  - Budget Material, 1971-1973 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 8)
  - Administrative Salaries, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 9)
  - Dean's Council, 1982 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 10)
  - GSPA Council, 1984 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 11)
  - GSPA Council, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 12)
  - Fall Admissions & Enrollment, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 13)
  - Enrollment Planning, 1979-1983 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 14)
  - Enrollments & Workload Analysis, 1971-1973 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 15)
  - Faculty Exchange, 1978-1981 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 16)
  - Status & Promotion, 1967-1975 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 17)
  - Committee on Promotion & Continuing Appointment, 1971-1974 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 18)
  - Faculty Memos, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (11-Oversized), Folder 19)
  - Assistantships & Fellowships, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 1)
  - GSPA, 1964-1968; 1979 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 2)
  - Meeting, 1974 February 26 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 3)
  - Validity of the States in Our Federal System - Mr. Joe Persico Governor's Office, 1972-73 Scheduling, 1977 Fall (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 4)
  - GSPA Faculty Reading Lists, 1967 Fall; 1968; 1971 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 5)
  - International Programs, 1969-1981 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 6)
  - Institutional Research, 1975-1983 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 7)
  - Dean's Day File - Political Science Department, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 8)
  - Dean's Day File - Political Science Department, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 9)
  - Public Administration Department, Spring Schedule, 1976 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 10)
  - Public Administration Department Schedule, 1975 Fall (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 11)
  - Dean's Day File, Public Administration Department, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 12)
  - Dean's Day File, Public Administration Department, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 13)
  - Dean's Day File, Public Affairs, 1972-1974 (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 14)
  - GSPA Student & Faculty Survey Questionnaires, 1973 April (Box 2 (11-Oversized), Folder 15)
  - Revised MA Program in Public Affairs, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 1)
  - Running Records, Letters of Inquiry (Public Affairs), 1971 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 2)
  - Programs, Schedules & Course Descriptions, Correspondence - Public Affairs Program, Center for Women in Government (CWIG), IPPA, 1973-1976; 1981-1983 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 3)
  - Institute for Government and Policy Studies (IGPS), 1987 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 4)
  - H. Applebaum, 1971 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 5)
  - H. Applebaum, 1970 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 6)
  - H. Applebaum, 1967 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 7)
  - H. Applebaum - Faculty Meetings, 1968 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 8)
  - M. Nathan Files - 0 & M 7 Management Controls Measurement Cost & Analysis Audit, 1946-1953 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 9)
  - M. Nathan Files - 0 & M 9 Records & Files Communication Business Machinery Space, ca. 1946-1947 (Box 3 (11-Oversized), Folder 10)
- Web Archives, 2014 January 15-2016 September 17; 12; 239 captures
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.
  Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu, library.albany.edu, events.albany.edu, cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Web Archives
  - http://www.albany.edu/rockefeller/homepage/ - University Archives collection, 2014 January 15-2016 September 17 (Web-archive 1)
  - WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/rockefeller/homepage/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details), 2014 January 15-2016 September 17 (Warc 1)
    WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.
  - http://www.albany.edu/rockefeller/homepage/ - Internet Archive collection, 2014 January 15-2016 September 17 (Web-archive 2)